<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>linux on Dhananjay's Blog</title><link>https://dhananjaylatkar.github.io/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in linux on Dhananjay's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Dhananjay</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:25:44 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dhananjaylatkar.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ext Linux Filesystem</title><link>https://dhananjaylatkar.github.io/posts/ext-linux-filesystem/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 21:36:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dhananjaylatkar.github.io/posts/ext-linux-filesystem/</guid><description>This post covers all versions of ext filesystem.
ext Created to overcome limitations of MINIX filesystem. First filesystem specificaly desined for Linux kernel. Restricted filename lengths to 255 characters and supported partitions up to 2GB. Major flaw - Allowed only one timestamp per file. ext2 Released less than year afer introduction of ext. Supported the maximum file size of 2TiB and filename can be 255 bytes long. Does not support journaling.</description></item><item><title>Extend btrfs root partition</title><link>https://dhananjaylatkar.github.io/posts/extend_btrfs_size/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:25:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dhananjaylatkar.github.io/posts/extend_btrfs_size/</guid><description>Introduction This article will demonstrate how to increase btrfs root partition size.
Use case:
In dual boot system (Fedora + Windows), use unsed disk space in Windows for Fedora. Steps Shrink Windows drive Boot into Windows. Shrink unsed drive using Disk Manager. Create partition Boot into Fedora. Use gpart (CLI) or Disks (GUI) to create partition. Check partition using lsblk. (nvme0n1p8 is newly created partition). ➜ sudo lsblk [sudo] password for dhananjay: NAME MAJ:MIN RM SIZE RO TYPE MOUNTPOINTS zram0 252:0 0 8G 0 disk [SWAP] nvme0n1 259:0 0 476.</description></item><item><title>Uninstall nix package manager from Linux</title><link>https://dhananjaylatkar.github.io/posts/nix-remove/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 16:56:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dhananjaylatkar.github.io/posts/nix-remove/</guid><description>Introduction As of Apr'22 nix package manager does not have official uninstaller. This post provides a way to remove nix. It can also be found in man page.
Uninstall NIX Remove nix related folders and Files
rm -rf $HOME/{.nix-channels,.nix-defexpr,.nix-profile,.config/nixpkgs} sudo rm -rf /nix Remove all references to nix in ~/.profile, ~/.bashrc and ~/.zshrc
Cleanup systemd
sudo systemctl stop nix-daemon.socket sudo systemctl stop nix-daemon.service sudo systemctl disable nix-daemon.</description></item><item><title>Compiling tbronzwaer/raptor</title><link>https://dhananjaylatkar.github.io/posts/raptor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 16:38:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://dhananjaylatkar.github.io/posts/raptor/</guid><description>Introduction This post documents steps required to compile tbronzwaer/raptor and use plotter.py
Dependencies Ubuntu 18.04 Install Ubuntu 18.04 as a VM. (https://releases.ubuntu.com/18.04/)
Build Dependencies sudo apt install gcc build-essential gfortran libpng-dev GNU Scientific computing Library (GSL) GSL needs to be compiled from source.
cd ~ git clone https://github.com/ampl/gsl.git cd gsl mkdir build &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cd build cmake .. -G&amp;#34;Unix Makefiles&amp;#34; -DNO_AMPL_BINDINGS=1 make sudo make install CBLAS library (Basic Linear Algebra Subprograms) Build blas_LINUX.</description></item></channel></rss>